Salim Djerbouh

BACKEND HEAVY · FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Résidence Ouarsenis, Akid Lotfi, Oran, Algeria

🛘 +213551081911 / +31629153326 | 💌 caddydz4@gmail.com | 🏕 dsalim.dev | 🖸 CaddyDz | 🖹 salim-djerbouh |

CaddyDz | ■ saly3301



Summary

Full-stack web developer and DevOps/SysAdmin. Extensive experience in developing and maintaining large web based applications. Over six years experience specializing in backend development, infrastructure engineering, CI/CD pipelines automation. Super nerd who loves Vim, macOS, Linux, enjoys setting up and customizing development environments. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools when the need arises.

Skills

DevOps Linux, Docker, Vagrant, Sentry, Travis CI, GitHub Actions, CloudFlare, Stripe, Algolia, Pusher, Heroku, Digital Ocean and GCP.

Back-end Laravel, NodeJS, MySQL, Redis, creating and consuming REST APIs.

Front-end Vue.js 2/3, VueX/Pinia, Nuxt JS, WebPack, Vite, HTML5, CSS3, Vuetify Material, Bootstrap, jQuery, Jekyll and Tailwind CSS.

Programming PHP, Javascript ES6, C#, Python, Shell Scripting, bits of Golang and Ruby.

Engineering Unit Testing QA and TDD, ACL, DAL, DTO, Modular architecture and web services.

Tools Jira, ClickUp, Notion, Obsidian, VCS (Git), Swagger and Postman.

Languages English, French and Arabic.

Work Experience _____

Zimou Express Oran, Algeria

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER May. 2023 - Present

- Built a billing module to manage subscriptions with a dashboard and subscribable webhooks.
- · Helped the manager organize the team's deliverables workflow thereby improving visibility of progress.
- Building modules integration setup for the ERP.

Upwork Remote

FREELANCE FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- Built a full-stack webapp for a financial management platform.
- Built a multitenancy modular architecture SaaS product.
- Built a full-stack webapp for a travel agency with Laravel and Vue.
- Fixing and/or improving deployment setups for various apps.

OrderSpark Remote, USA (Freelance)

BACKEND DEVELOPER, DEVOPS LEAD

- Built management portal UI and backend (Laravel Nova).
- Built marketing site API.
- Handled all DevOps infrastructure and software architecture.
- Organized, secured, cleaned up and documented system resources thereby reducing operating costs.

One Potato, Ltd Remote, USA (Freelance)

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- Setup a staging server/environment eliminating bugs in acceptance phase.
- Redesigned the deliveries page significantly improving the user experience.
- Fixed frontend edge cases bugs.
- Refactored and cleaned up parts of the codebase to enhance maintainability.
- Developed a weekly total billing component.

American National Hockey League.

BACKEND ENGINEER, DEVOPS

- Debugging and maintaining a Django framework based admin panel.
- Connecting uploaded audio file briefs to AWS S3 with Amazon Alexa.
- Maintaining deployments on Heroku.
- Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.

Remote, USA (Freelance)

Jan. 2022 - May. 2022

Jan. 2023 - Present

Oct. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Oct. 2022 - Dec. 2023

Shyfter, SRL.

Brussels, Belgium (Remote)

BACKEND ENGINEER, DEVOPS ASSIST

Feb. 2021 - Aug 2022

- Integrated government services with compliance to security requirements like Dimona and audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- · Switched deployment infrastructure improving runtime performance by 34% and reducing costs by almost 900%.
- Worked on customer exclusive features and requirements.
- Built Redis based queue system and moved long processing operations to background jobs.
- · Migrated legacy codebase from pure procedural PHP to resusable service classes resulting maintainability.
- · Refactored code base reducing algorithmic complexity and also enforced coding standards for consistency.
- Built a printable dynamic GATT documents and assisted frontend team on API consumption.

Salesforce, Inc San Francisco, California (Remote)

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

June. 2021 - December 2021

- · Wrote the full test-suite for Unit, Feature and Browser QA tests.
- Developed and maintained CI/CD pipeline on GitHub with actions and Heroku deployments as well as review apps on branches connecting
 everything to Jira development board.
- Audited and mitigated unnoticed security advisories.
- Eliminated bottle-neck performance issues.
- Improved managers users invite experience by building bulk CSV imports/exports.
- Improved UX by building a campaign flow saver.
- Added a way for managers to flag users as (free access) so they don't get charged via Stripe.
- · Automated fixing Salesforce branding via GitHub actions.

Zidweb, LLC. Oran, Algeria

CO-FOUNDER, CTO AND LEAD DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Provisioned an easily manageable hybrid infrastructure(Digital Ocean Droplets + On-premise) utilizing IaC tools like Sentry and OpenVPN.
- Manage all DevOps and third party services integration (CloudFlare, Forge, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage).
- Implemented, documented RESTful API server for directory listing application.
- Wrote and deployed several small scale apps like shopping carts.
- · Restructured a +40 million records database of automotive spare parts catalog and implemented a web interface for it.
- Created Backend in Laravel + Frontend in NuxtJS for an ELO Boosting gaming service.

Didata LLC.Zürich, Switzerland

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

March. 2019 - April. 2020

- Wrote example testing data seeders for BioLab research application.
- Implemented an ACL architecture for Backend API.
- Wrote mutations mapping module for state management following the Flux pattern for the Frontend application.
- Implemented several CRUD models.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2016-2023 Top %4, Overall Stack Overflow members.

International

2018-2020 **Top #37**, PHP ranking GitHub awards.

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Presentation

GDG Conference Blida, Algeria

PRESENTER FOR < MACHINE LEARNING THEORY>

Nov. 2017

- · Introduced the theory of machine learning genetic algorithms with an analogy of evolutionary biology.
- Introduced how machine learning algorithms work with an implementation of an SAT resolver in symbolic regression.

OpenMinds Linux install party

Algiers, Algeria

SPEAKER < A LOOK INTO THE KERNEL INTERNALS>

Apr. 2017

· A brief talk about the Linux kernel source tree and subsystems with a short introduction to OSDev.

Education

Lounici Ali University

Blida, Algeria

FINAL YEAR ENGLISH LITERATURE

Sep. 2013 - Jan. 2016

- American history, civilization & literature.
- Studied English linguistics and works of Noam Chomsky.